<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sebastian Pycior</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Sebastian Pycior</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2016. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Find a quarterback for 2019</title>
      <link>/post/find-a-quarterback-for-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/find-a-quarterback-for-2019/</guid>
      <description>Haven’t you heard? The NFL cough owners and bad management cough is terrible at drafting the right quarterback. My advice? Don’t overthink it.
Average yards per pass attempts and qb rate in a quarterbacks collegiate career should be enough to show everyone which prospects should be good enough for NFL development. Below, I’m trying to stay away from claiming who’s the best and instead am trying to show that thinking quarterbacks shouldn’t be too complicated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NCAA MB Categorical Analysis</title>
      <link>/post/ncaa-mb-categorical-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/ncaa-mb-categorical-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Below is an updating categorical analysis report on American college basketball recruits heading to the 2019 NBA Draft. The report matches 2018-2019 NCAAMB statistics from sports-reference to Aran Smith’s 2019 Big Board: Top 100 Prospects. The report methodology is based on Ed Weiland’s analysis, which I took and retooled just a bit. Here, I first wrote using the analysis at Nylon Calculus for the 2018 NBA Draft class.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using VORP to pay college basketball players</title>
      <link>/post/using-vorp-to-pay-college-basketball-players/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/using-vorp-to-pay-college-basketball-players/</guid>
      <description>VORP should be used to pay players in college basketball, or at least be the first steps towards achieving some kind of salary distribution system for college hoops. The following table shows salaries of every Men’s College Basketball Athlete’s potential salary based on the VORP metric and a NBA based unionization agreement between college athletes and the NCAA.
##Legend
Data Source: Sports-Reference.com</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tools</title>
      <link>/tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tools/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the tools page. Below are links to posts that have interactive data tables or Shiny apps.
NCAA MB Categorical Analysis
Using VORP to pay Men&amp;rsquo;s College Basketball athletes</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Education
University of Washington, 2009-2013
Bachelor&amp;rsquo;s of Arts
Political Science, Mathematics Minor
When I&amp;rsquo;m not working or watching basketball, I&amp;rsquo;m probably drinking a ton of coffee or watching a good ol&amp;rsquo; British murder mystery with my wife. I also own a dog named Penny, a yellow lab. We hike, play and eat with her.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contact/</guid>
      <description>Email: sebasp41@gmail.com
Based in the Seattle, WA area</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>