<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Sebastian Pycior</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Sebastian Pycior</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2016. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Car Death Rates and Dimensions</title>
      <link>/post/car-death-rates-and-dimensions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/car-death-rates-and-dimensions/</guid>
      <description>What makes a car dangerous to drive for a consumer? There are plenty of variables to consider and for this entry in particular I wanted to see if car dimensions were significantly related to death rates in vehicles.
Using R I’m going to review the data at hand, visualize it and then work through a multiple regression analysis.
Car Deaths and Car Dimension Data I retrieved car death rate data from the IIHS available by make and model here for the years 2001-2017 (years ’99-’01 are TBD).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tableau Viz - Washington Post Police Shootings</title>
      <link>/post/washington-post-police-shootings/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/washington-post-police-shootings/</guid>
      <description>This Tableau visualization using the database compiled by the Washington Post. More on the WaPo data here:
https://www.washingtonpost.com/graphics/2019/national/police-shootings-2019/
Initially, I didn’t have any particular interest in police fatalities, nor have I ever really studied the matter. I originally wanted to just find data that felt alive and held significance. When I came across the WaPo fatal force data, I definitely felt that there was important significance to the dataset.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NBA - Plotly BMI and DPIPM Overview</title>
      <link>/post/nba-plotly-bmi-and-dpipm-overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/nba-plotly-bmi-and-dpipm-overview/</guid>
      <description>Basketball, size and defense. This season especially, I felt it important to analyze what teams looked like, and how that look - as defined by BMI - translated alongside an advanced defensive metric in DPIPM(from bball-index).
Working on a writeup for my analysis soon. But for now, I’ve included a Tableau visualization for players’ respective BMI vs. DPIPM grouped by a k-means cluster. Tableau k-means methods can be found here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Find a quarterback for 2019</title>
      <link>/post/find-a-quarterback-for-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/find-a-quarterback-for-2019/</guid>
      <description>Haven’t you heard? The NFL cough owners and bad management cough is terrible at drafting the right quarterback. My advice? Don’t overthink it.
Average yards per pass attempts and qb rate in a quarterbacks collegiate career should be enough to show everyone which prospects should be good enough for NFL development. Below, I’m trying to stay away from claiming who’s the best and instead am trying to show that thinking quarterbacks shouldn’t be too complicated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NCAA MB Categorical Analysis</title>
      <link>/post/ncaa-mb-categorical-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/ncaa-mb-categorical-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Below is an updating categorical analysis report on American college basketball recruits heading to the 2019 NBA Draft. The report matches 2018-2019 NCAAMB statistics from sports-reference to Aran Smith’s 2019 Big Board: Top 100 Prospects. The report methodology is based on Ed Weiland’s analysis, which I took and retooled just a bit. Here, I first wrote using the analysis at Nylon Calculus for the 2018 NBA Draft class.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using VORP to pay college basketball players</title>
      <link>/post/using-vorp-to-pay-college-basketball-players/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/using-vorp-to-pay-college-basketball-players/</guid>
      <description>VORP should be used to pay players in college basketball, or at least be the first steps towards achieving some kind of salary distribution system for college hoops. The following table shows salaries of every Men’s College Basketball Athlete’s potential salary based on the VORP metric and a NBA based unionization agreement between college athletes and the NCAA.
##Legend
Data Source: Sports-Reference.com</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
